Guide to the Albert Ellis papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Audio Visual Material, 1953-2007
  - Subseries V.2: Reel to Reel Audio, 1953-1975
    - Tensilized Polyester 5 in. reel, 0.5 mil, 1200 ft.
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Great Issues. WNYC-TV. TV-Time Recordings, 1964 January 9)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Barry Gray Show. WMCA. TV-Time Recordings, 1963 March 16)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (IRL Workshop, Washington. Side 1: a. 45-yr old woman, guilty about working and at times leaving 13-yr-old son alone. b. 30-yr old male, demndg guarantee of success and pleasure. Side 2: 3-yr old girl who can’t relate to Father, 1967 September 3)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Dr. Maxie Maultsby. "Lousy sound quality," Undated)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Guest presentation, N.S.B. Television, Atlanta, Georgia, "Today in Georgia." Dr. AE, Dr. Ray Cleare, Dr. Henry Harsch, with Mr. Charlie Welch, 1969 February 27)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Dr. AE and Joe Pyne, cont. of Ellis and Pyne, Undated)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Calif. Community Discussion Grp., reactions to Ellis talk at Beverly Hill H.S., rebroadcast-Title of talk was "Sex, Sanity, and Psychotherapy." 1964 November 13)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (BEWAD, UTSGL, ETSMA, IEWRO, EITAN, LEBED, OHTMA, REWLI, 1968 March 5, 7, 15, 16)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (1. Rolf, Ellen, Sam, VILHY, REBCA, AVEJA, LEZBO, 1970 March 26, 27; 2. YOPLI, ROWST, SOKTE, HCSED, ARKNA, NRANA, 1970 March 27)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (RABCA, REGDA, CUBSA, Thurs 7:00 Grp, Thurs 8:45 group, VILHY, MISAR, ROWEL, 1970 April 2, 3)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (REFPE, ROMAL, ARKNO, Fr. Group, ORBGL, ETSGE, NEPHI, LOBAL, TIBAD, Monday 7:00 pm grp, UOYDA, 1970 April 3, 6, 7)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (1. LOSJO, ZALBE, LEFAR, Mon 8:45 grp, ARKMA, UOYDA, 1970 April 20, 21; 2. REGDA, WOLSY, Tues 8:15 grp, LIWBO, ERFRO, 1970 April 21)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (1. TUDAL, DURCL, 1972 February 4; 2. a. blank, b. woman incapble of doing anythg, Undated)
    - Nassau recording tape, 3.25 in. reel
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Two reels: L.L. 1966 October; L.L., Undated)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 216)
        (Two reels: L.L. 1967 February18; First part of talk to Queens U.N. Assoc. Can Knowledge of Ourselves Prevent War, 1967 March 12)
    - 1 mil Mylar base, 1200 ft.
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 214)
        (Ellis Seminar, presented by AE. Tape 2. Side 1: Interview with Tim, a young Schizophrenic. Side 2: Interview with Mrs. S., middle-aged paranoid. Afternoon session. Arizona State Hospital, 1967 May 8)
      - Reel to Reel Audio: (Box 214)
        (Ellis Seminar, presented by AE. Tape 3. Side 1: Basic Irrationalities--Theory. Side 2: Same as above, with discussion following, Morning session, 1967 May 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes related to Reel to Reel Audio: 1968 October 23, October 26-November 2, November 6-7, 11-12, 27-29, 1969 February 3-5, December 18 (Box 216)
- Subseries V.3: VHS, 1989-2003
  Subseries V.3 contains tapes on RET, Ret Symposiums, and Ellis interviews.
  - RET, Circa 1989 (Hebrew) (Box 116)
  - The Milton H. Erickson Foundation, Inc., "The Evolution of Psychotherapy, A Conference," Live Demonstrations of Ration-Emotive Therapy, Albert Ellis, 1990 (Box 116)
  - RET Symposium, Tape 3, 1990 September 28 (Box 116)
  - "60 Minutes"-- Werner Erhard--1. Original Broadcast, 2. Letters One Week Later, 1991 March (Box 116)
  - Foundations of Rational Emotive Therapy, Parts I through III, The German Institute for Rational Emotive Therapy and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy, 1991 March 3 (German) (Box 116)
  - Dalai Lama, Santa Barbara, 1991 April 7 (Box 116)
  - Editing Workshop--Cynthia Brown and Mike McClintock, 1997 April, May (Box 116)
  - Mandate and Policies, DINAH, 1998 March 10 (Box 116)
  - Balance Television for Living Well, EP # 1-095, Channel Nine Court, Agincourt, Ontario, Canada, 2003 May 10 (Box 116)
  - Eigo Business World, Albert Ellis Institute, Undated (Box 116)
  - Elmhurst College IMC, Undated (Box 116)
- Subseries V.4: Dictabelt Records, 1954-1965
  This subseries contains dictabelts that span slightly more than a decade.
  - 1955-1965, (15 belts) (Box 66)
  - 1959, Undated, (10 belts) (Box 66)
  - 1955-1959, (20 belts) (Box 66)
  - 1954-1955, (11 belts) (Box 66)
  - 1955-1956, (11 belts) (Box 66)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1920-2004
  These materials are arranged chronologically. Included are photographs of Dr. Ellis's talks and workshops around the world, in his study, and portraits by various studios. A variety of casual shots, both alone and with others, can also be found.
  - Photocopy -- Albert Ellis With Hettie, Paul, and Janet Ellis, 1920 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, " Around 35", 1948 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, [1953] (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Rhoda Russell, 1956 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 1961 April (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Janet Wolfe, 1965-1968 1998 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis and "Sex Without Guilt", [1965] (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits by Fabian Bachrach, [1965] (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits With Frames, 1966 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Author Photos and Layouts, 1967 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Hope Powell, 1970 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits by Blackstone-Shelburne N.Y., 1972 January (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis photo by Janet L. Wolfe, 1972 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals in London, 1974 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jack Gordon and Bob Sharpe in London, 1974 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, 1974 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Terry London, 1974 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Syracuse University, 1975 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Harry Benjamin, 1975 January 10 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, 1975 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With three Unidentified Individuals, 1975 Fall (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Giving a Talk, Location Unknown, 1976 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jane Higbee, [1977] (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Bill Knaus, 1977 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Arnold Lazarus, [1978] (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual in Los Angeles, 1978 April (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual at Mobile, Alabama Workshop, 1978 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, 1978 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Christine Coe and Mary Sullivan, 1979 January (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Richard Kujoth, 1979 February (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Family Planning Association of India, Rational Therapy Applied to Sexual Problems, Bombay, India, 1980 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Roast, New York, 1980 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Lugano, Switzerland, 1980 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis at RET workshop, Kansas City, Missouri, 1981 February 28 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis in Austin, Texas, 1981 May 30 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual at a Workshop, 1982 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Janet Wolfe, and Unidentified Individual, 1982 September (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Ian Campbell, 1983 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis in West Germany, 1983 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Carolyn Morley, Unidentified Individual, 1983 April (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals in Kuwait, 1983 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Association for the Advancement of Behaviour Therapy (AABT), 1983 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Maureen G.M. Keith, 1984 February (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Sarah Ruma, 1985 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 1985 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With [Ian Campbell], 1985 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Cynthia Stone and Unidentified Individuals, 1985 February 19 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Morehead State University, Kentucky, 1985 April (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Greg Potter, 1985 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 1985 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Mrs. Plumb, Unidentified Individuals, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1985 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis "Taken by Susan Walen", 1986 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Hans Lehfeldt, 1986 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Gina Gibson, 1986 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jane A. Miller, 1986 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals in Las Vegas, 1986 October (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With M. Bowler, MichAlbert Ellisl Bernard, Unidentified Individuals, Melbourne, Australia, 1986 October (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Carolyn Morley Shago and Lynn Houseal in Las Vegas, 1986 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Rosselina, 1986 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 1987 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Maurits Klee, Amsterdam, 1987 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Society for the Scientific Study of Sexuality Meeting, Atlanta, 1987 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Sugiura, Ishikama, Suganuma, Saito, Hasegawa, Murase, and Yasutaka Kokubu and Idisako Kokubo, Tokyo, Japan, 1987 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual, Amsterdam, 1988 April (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual, APA Convention, Atlanta, 1988 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Promotion Shot and Layout, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Oxford, 1989 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, 1989 November (Box 94)
  - "Albert Ellis Singing His Rational Songs," 1990 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Assoc. Practicum, 1990 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis "by Joel Dames," 1990 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Stuart Kaplowitz, Fullerton, California, 1990 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis "by Kyoko Nognahi," 1991 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Candee Guterman, 1991 August 26 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jeff Guterman, 1991 August 26 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Fahmida Majid, 1991 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jerry Davison, 1991 November 23 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Frank Marquit, 1992 March 6 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Rhoda Russell, 1992 April 12 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Polly Wilde, Jerry, Chicago, 1992 May (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Marc Calderon, and Unidentified Individual, 1992 July 11 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, CCNY Townsend Harris Award, 1992 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals on a Panel, 1993 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Kumiko Yoshioka, 1993 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Gary Pinder, 1993 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Giving a Demonstration of REBT in the Netherlands, 1993 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, "Dr. Ellis in his office," 1993 February (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis and Susie Kim, 1993 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Hans Eysenek, William Williams at Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference, Hamburg, Germany, 1993 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Frank Belczyk, 1993 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Pavel N. Ivanoff, 1994 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis and Lyle Stuart, 1995 August 13 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With an audience Member of his Friday Night Workshop, 1995 October (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Postcard (Dutch), 1996 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Tony Kidman, 1996 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Kikuo Uchiyama, 1996 March (Box 94)
  - Newsprint--"Counseling Today"--Albert Ellis With Earl Gintor, Joyce Breasure, Don C. Locke, Allen Ivey, Jeffrey Guterman, Sandra Rigazio-Digilio, 1996 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Joel Ginsburg, 1996 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis and Hilda Van der Steen, 1996 July (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, APA, 1996 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Arnold Lazarus, APA, 1996 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits by Beebe Willoughby, 1996 October (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Chiara Tassone, 1996 November 22 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Jeff Zeig, San Francisco, 1996 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Janet Wolfe, Hank Robb, Ricks Warren, Ray DiGuiseppe, and Emmet Velton, AABT, 1996 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With David Ellis, Susan Ellis, and Their Daughters, 1997 January (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Montreal, 1998 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Debbie Joffe Ellis and Unidentified Individuals, APA, San Francisco, 1998 August (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Wurzburg, Germany, 1998 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals at the Puerto Rican Counseling Association, 1998 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals at Dept of Juvenile Corrections, Tucson, Arizona, 1998 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 2000 September 22 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, 2000 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Debbie Joffe Ellis, Diane Dillon, and Chris Fives, 2001 January (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With David Burns, Colorado, 2001 June (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, AABT, Philadelphia, 2001 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Debbie Joffe Ellis, 2000 December, 2002 January, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, 2002 January (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Debbie Joffe Ellis, Kristene Doyle, and Unidentified Individuals, 2002 February (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified "English interviewer", 2002 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Debbie Joffe Ellis, and Unidentified Individual, 2002 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Children, 2002 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual, 2002 December (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis and Debbie Joffe, 2003 September (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individual, 2003 November (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals--Correspondence From Martine, "holidays", 2004 (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Debbie Joffe Ellis, and Unidentified Individuals, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis at the New York Hilton at Rockefeller Center, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, Friday Night Workshop at Albert Ellis Institute, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis, "Journals" page 31, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits by Fabian Bachrach, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits/proofs by Irwin Gooen, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits by Neil Polen, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis Portraits taped to cardboard, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis--Various shots in Black and White, Undated, (3 folders) (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis--Various Shots in Color, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Maxie Maultsby, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, AAP Workshop, "6/16", Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Individuals, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Unidentified Man at Conference, Undated (Box 94)
  - Albert Ellis With Carole Stuart, Janet Wolfe, Lyle Stuart, Undated (Box 94)
  - Holiday card -- Albert Ellis, Kristene Doyle, and Unidentified Individuals, signed by Ann, Steve, Raph, Chris, Rocio, Kristene, Erinn musser, Rick H..., Dana Lieber, Undated (Box 94)